A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Projects FA733
Rockefeller Archive Center
- D-54: Illinois Commission of Higher Education - Unified administration of three state controlled institutions of higher education in Illinois, 1960 (Reel P-1022)
- D-55: Yale University (Bingham Oceanographic Laboratory) - Expansion of program in oceanography, 1960 (Reel P-1022)
- D-58: Claremont Men's College [Claremont McKenna College] - Scholarship program in liberal arts colleges, 1960 (Reel P-1022)
- D-61: University of Michigan - Inter-university consortium for political research, 1959-1960 (Reel P-1022)
- D-62: Goucher College - Seminar on "Human Values in the Emerging American City", 1960 (Reel P-1022)
- D-63: European Productivity Agency - Investigation into management education in Europe, 1960 (Reel P-1022)
- D-64: European Productivity Agency - Russian achievements in certain scientific fields, 1960 (Reel P-1022)
- D-66: Lake Forest College - Adjusting from a two-degree program to a one-degree program, 1960 (Reel P-1022)
- D-69: University of Rochester - Department of Electrical Engineering, 1960 (Reel P-1022)
- D-70: University of Chicago - Research center on Africa, 1960 (Reel P-1022)
- D-71: Facilities (Washington International Ceter) for foreign visitors in Washington, D.C. (Ford Foundation initiated), 1959 (Reel P-1022)
- D-74: Mississippi College - Program in business-economic education, 1960 (Reel P-1022)
- D-76: Michigan State University - Language honors institute for high school students, 1960 (Reel P-1022)
- D-80: International Council of Scientific Unions - General support, 1960 (Reel P-1022)
- D-81: Pratt Institute - Study of preparation of teachers for field of engineering, 1960 (Reel P-1022)
- D-86: Newark College of Engineering Research Foundation - Program for teachers of engineering, 1960 (Reel P-1022)
- D-93: Atlantic Treaty Association - Three year educational programme, 1960 (Reel P-1022)
- D-97: Food and Agricultural Organization of the United Nations - Sources and causes of increased agricultural production in different countries, 1960 (Reel P-1022)
- D-98: National Council of Women of the United States, Inc. - Exchange of persons between the Soviet Union and United States, 1960 (Reel P-1022)
- D-99: Williams College - Grant-In-Aid for the Roper Public Opinion Research Center, 1960 (Reel P-1022)
- D-101: Hollins College - Research, field work and participation in politics, 1960 (Reel P-1022)
- D-107: University of Miami - Survey and study of progress made in metropolitan Dade County, Florida, 1960 (Reel P-1022)
- D-109: Huston-Tillotson College - Public affairs program of the Citizenship Education Foundation, 1960 (Reel P-1022)
- D-110: College of the Pacific - New college of liberal arts, 1960 (Reel P-1022)
- D-111: Austrian Society for Research in Atomic Energy - Laboratories of high activities of the Austrian research center, 1960 (Reel P-1022)
- D-112: American University at Cairo - Establishment of a documentation center, 1959-1960 (Reel P-1022)
- D-117: National Commission of Accrediting - Improved methods of accreditation and evaluating quality in higher education, 1960 (Reel P-1022)
- D-119: International Federation of Petroleum Workers - Educational programs in under-developed areas for trade unionists, 1960 (Reel P-1022)
- D-120: New York University - Training of scientists in atmospheric sciences, 1960 (Reel P-1022)
- D-123: Texas Southern University - Stimulation and development of responsible citizenship, 1960 (Reel P-1022)
- D-124: Lansing Public Schools - Videotape of three year spanish course for elementary schools, 1960 (Reel P-1022)
- D-126: Claremont Graduate School - Fellowships for advanced degree students in academic year 1960-1961. (Reel P-1022)
- D-129: Research and development in juvenile deliquency control Ford Foundation initiated), 1960 (Reel P-1022)
- D-130: University of Washington, Seattle - Interim study of state of Washington's educational system, 1960 (Reel P-1022)
- D-131: Studies of urban renewal (Ford Foundation initiated), 1960 (Reel P-1022)
- D-132: Schools and urban "Gray Areas" (Ford Foundation initiated, Education and Public Affairs programs), 1960 (Reel P-1022)
- D-137: Population program (Ford Foundation initiated), 1958-1960 (Reel P-1023)
- D-140: Board of Christian Education; Presbyterian Church in the United States - Experimental teaching clinics for improvement of college teaching, 1960 (Reel P-1023)
- D-141: Union College - Apprentice scholars program, 1960 (Reel P-1023)
- D-142: Council for Economic Growth and Security - Study of the problem of inflation, 1960 (Reel P-1023)
- D-143: Institute for British-American Cultural Exchange, Inc. - Interchange of students between Great Britain and United States, 1960 (Reel P-1023)
- D-144: University of Texas - Optimum employment of modern educational media in the education of teachers, 1960 (Reel P-1023)
- D-147: American Educational Theatre Association, Inc. - Theatre arts instruction in the secondary schools, 1960 (Reel P-1023)
- D-148: American Educational Theatre Association, Inc. - Study of contemporary German theatre architecture, 1960 (Reel P-1023)
- D-149: American-Swiss Foundation for Scientific Exchange, Inc. - Exchange program for American and Swiss scientists, 1960 (Reel P-1023)
- D-151: Foundation for World Literacy - Method for teaching literacy in English, 1960 (Reel P-1023)
- D-153: American Friends Service Committee - East-West seminar exchange program, 1960 (Reel P-1023)
- D-154: Minnesota Department of Education - Summer television program for mathematics teachers, 1960 (Reel P-1023)
- D-155: University of Puerto Rico - Research program for improvement of education, 1960 (Reel P-1023)
- D-159: University of Minnesota - Support of laboratory facilities adapted to science oriented engineering curricula, 1960 (Reel P-1023)
- D-161: Michigan State University - Center for civil defense and disaster control, 1960 (Reel P-1023)
- D-162: University of Cairo - Textbooks for engineering students, 1960 (Reel P-1023)
- D-169: Harvard University - Asian center for management research and development in the Philippines, 1960-1961 (Reel P-1023)
- D-171: University of California, Berkeley - University extension program in urban affairs, 1960-1961 (Reel P-1023)
- D-173: Clarkson College of Technology - Study of the graduate and research program, 1960 (Reel P-1023)
- D-175: Washington State Association of County Commissioners - Demonstration of value of functional consolidation of local government, 1960 (Reel P-1023)
- D-177: University of Texas - Activities of the division of educational psychology, 1960 (Reel P-1023)
- D-178: California Department of the Youth Authority; Department of Corrections - Pilot project in correctional case work training, 1960 (Reel P-1023)
- D-180: Purdue University - New Program and curriculum in the division of engineering sciences, 1960 (Reel P-1023)
- D-184: University of Akron - Program for teachers of foreign languages in public schools, 1960 (Reel P-1023)
- D-185: University of North Carolina - Inter-American forum, 1960 (Reel P-1023)
- D-188: Clarkson College of Technology - Experimental program for gifted students in engineering and science, 1960 (Reel P-1023)
- D-189: American-Asian Educational Exchange, Inc. - Conference on "Communist China, the Powers, and United States Policy", 1960 (Reel P-1023)
- D-191: Stanford University - Stanford overseas program, European centers, 1960 (Reel P-1023)
- D-192: University of Wyoming - Establishment of an office for business and governmental training programs, 1960 (Reel P-1023)
- D-193: Bucknell University - Pre-session institute for the newly elected member of Pennsylvania's general assembly, 1960 (Reel P-1023)
- D-194: Johns Hopkins University - Support for the department of fine arts, 1960 (Reel P-1023)
- D-195: Hope College - Study of the impact of short term rehabilitation on the young adult offender, 1960 (Reel P-1023)
- D-197: Indiana University - Support for school of business, 1960-1961 (Reel P-1023)
- D-198: Milwaukee Vocational and Adult Schools - Study of educational television, 1960 (Reel P-1023)
- D-200: Research and Planning Council - Survey of metropolitan government in Bexar County, Texas, 1960 (Reel P-1023)
- D-207: Rochester Area Educational Television Association, Inc. - Program in educational television, 1960 (Reel P-1023)
- D-208: Fellowship program in business administration and economics (Ford Foundation initiated), 1960 (Reel P-1023)
- D-209: Teachers College, Columbia University - Strengthening research and training in comparative education, 1960 (Reel P-1023, Reel P-1024)
- D-210: Research and Action Projects on Juvenile Delinquency (Ford Foundation initiated), 1960 (Reel P-1024)
- D-211: Evaulation of Neighborhood Centered Deliquency Prevention Program (Ford Foundation initiated), 1960 (Reel P-1024)
- D-212: Speaker Services for the United States - General program, 1960 (Reel P-1024)
  "Funds for expansion of reginal subcenters, payment of speakers' fees and travel, annual conferences and extend circulation of 'Speakers Notes'". Includes material from Eleanor Roosevelt. Proposal rejected, 7/14/1960.
- D-215: American-Korean Foundation, Inc. - Return transportation for Korean students, 1960 (Reel P-1024)
- D-217: Messiah College (Granthem, Pennsylvania) - African studies program, 1960 (Reel P-1024)
- D-218: National Council on the Arts and Government - Conference, 1960 (Reel P-1024)
- D-219: Iowa State University of Science and Technology - Empirical evaluation of decision rules, 1960 (Reel P-1024)
- D-220: U.S. National Committee for the Preservation of Nubian Monuments, 1960 (Reel P-1024)
- D-223: University of Kansas - Future developments on education for business, 1960 (Reel P-1024)
- D-225: University of Chicago - Federal-College internship program in Chicago area, 1960-1961 (Reel P-1024)
- D-234: University of Virginia - Educational program of Thomas Jefferson Center for Studies in Political Economy, 1960 (Reel P-1024)
- D-241: University of Minnesota - Language research and materials development laboratory, 1960 (Reel P-1024)
- D-242: Port Jervis Board of Education, New York - Developing community support for educational television, 1960 (Reel P-1024)
- D-244: Seven College [Seven Sisters] Conference - General support, 1960 (Reel P-1024)
- D-249: Northwestern University - Programs of the technological institute, 1960-1961 (Reel P-1024)
- D-251: University of Leeds - Research unit on comparative endocrinology, 1960 (Reel P-1024)
- D-253: The Kossuth Foundation, Inc. - Institute for economic development and research in the Congo, 1960 (Reel P-1024)
- D-254: American Society for Engineering Education - Projects management group, 1960 (Reel P-1024)
- D-255: Smith College - Programs of study in American government and politics, 1960 (Reel P-1024)
- D-258: Summer research seminars for college teachers of economics (Ford Foundation initiated), 1960-1963 (Reel P-1024)
- D-261: Grinnell College - Summer education programs, 1960 (Reel P-1024)
- D-262: Improvement of doctoral engineering education in the South (Ford Foundation initiated), 1960 (Reel P-1024)
- D-263: Rehabilitation of delinquent boys (Ford Foundation initiated), 1960 (Reel P-1024)
- D-264: International Cooperation Administration - Study of feasibility of a Point Four Youth Corps
- D-265: DePauw University - Investigate the relation of decision making behavior to academic underachievement, 1960 (Reel P-1024)
- D-267: Institute of Early American History and Culture - General program, 1960 (Reel P-1024)
- D-269: University of Notre Dame - State industrial development programs, 1960 (Reel P-1024)
- D-270: Special Programs in Education (Ford Foundation initiated), 1960 (Reel P-1024, Reel P-1025)
- D-271: Wayne State University - Relationship between police youth bureaus and repeating offenders, 1960 (Reel P-1025)
- D-272: American Institute for Research, Washington D.C. - Use of self-instructional devices in the treatment of youthful offenders, 1960 (Reel P-1025)
- D-275: City of Milwaukee - Study of social and cultural problems in the city of Milwaukee, 1960-1963 (Reel P-1025)
- D-276: University of Texas - Pilot or test seminar for state trial judges, 1960 (Reel P-1025)
- D-279: High Point College - Education for leadership, 1960 (Reel P-1025)
- D-281: Cleveland Welfare Federation - Hough community development project, 1961 (Reel P-1025)
- D-282: State of Wisconsin, Department of Resource Development - Planning demonstration program, 1960-1961 (Reel P-1025)
- D-283: Expiremental demonstration and evaluation projects relating to critical foreign languages (Ford Foundation initiated), 1960 (Reel P-1025)
- D-286: Columbia University - Preparation of a compilation of constitutions, 1960 (Reel P-1025)
- D-291: University of Texas - Metropolitan and regional planning research and education, 1960 (Reel P-1025)
- D-292: Kent State University - Aid to graduate education in business administration, 1960 (Reel P-1025)
- D-294: Experiment in International Living - Homestay orientation program for African students, 1960-1961 (Reel P-1025)
- D-297: United States National Commission for UNESCO - Support for eigth national conference, 1960-1961 (Reel P-1025)
- D-303: Lincoln University - Orientation program for newly arrived African students, 1960-1961 (Reel P-1025)
- D-304: New York University - Brazilian institute at New York University, 1960-1961 (Reel P-1025)
- D-309: New York University - Community oriented drug addition program, 1960 (Reel P-1025)
- D-313: American College Public Relations Association - General support, 1960 (Reel P-1025)
- D-316: Tulane University - Latin American legal research center, 1960 (Reel P-1025)
- D-319: Legislative internship program (Ford Foundation initiated), 1960 (Reel P-1025)
- D-321: Cornell University - Encyclopedia of management decision-making sources, 1961 (Reel P-1025)
- D-325: Washington D.C. Board of Commissioners - World conference of local governments, 1961 (Reel P-1025)
- D-326: International Christian University, Tokyo, Japan - Teaching of Japanese as a second language, 1961-1963 (Reel P-1025)
- D-328: Experimental program of forgivable loans to doctoral engineering students motivated toward engineering teaching (Ford Foundation initiated), 1961 (Reel P-1025)
- D-329: University of Natal [South Africa] - Fellowships for studying the problems of emergent Africa, 1961 (Reel P-1025)
- D-330: University of Cincinnati - Experimental plan of cooperative teacher education, 1961-1962 (Reel P-1025)
- D-331: University of the Philippines - Support for graduate program, 1961 (Reel P-1025)
- D-334: Athens Technological Institute - Support programs of the junior technical colleges, 1961 (Reel P-1025)
- D-337: New York University - Integration of curricula in geophysics, 1961 (Reel P-1025)
- D-338: University of Chicago - Cross-national project on the evaluation of educational attainment, 1961 (Reel P-1025)
- D-339: DePauw University - Development of the physics department, 1961 (Reel P-1025)
- D-342: Upper Midwest Research and Development Council - Establish an upper midwest research institute, 1961 (Reel P-1026)
- D-345: Kansas State Teachers College - Kansas institute on international affairs, 1961 (Reel P-1026)
- D-347: Ohio State University - Experiment on Ph.D. education in metallurgy, 1961 (Reel P-1026)
- D-348: Oregon State System of Higher Education - Improving the quality of continuing higher education, 1961 (Reel P-1026)
- D-350: Athens Technological Institute - An economic survey of Greece, 1961 (Reel P-1026)
- D-351: Oglethorpe University - Development of efficiency in a small operation, 1961 (Reel P-1026)
- D-352: Cooper Union for the Advancement of Science and Art - Educational program in the creative arts, 1961 (Reel P-1026)
- D-354: New York University - Working party to aid Puerto Rican education, 1961 (Reel P-1026)
- D-359: Whitworth College - Program in science education, 1961 (Reel P-1026)
- D-360: American Economic Association - Program of congressional fellowships in economics, 1961 (Reel P-1026)
- D-361: University of Kentucky - Improvement of communication skills among public school students in a depressed, coal mining area, 1961 (Reel P-1026)
- D-365: South African Institute of Race Relations - Support for research and investigation, 1961 (Reel P-1026)
- D-366: Consultant of program of economic analysis to committee for coordination of investigations of lower Mekong basin (Ford Foundation initiated), 1960 (Reel P-1027, Reel P-1026)
- D-368: University of Southern California - Study of the social movements of the Arab, Near East, and North Africa, 1961 (Reel P-1028)
- D-369: United Nations - Assistance to under-developed countries in the study of population problems (Reel P-1028)
- D-370: American Nuclear Society - Organization and program of the committee on units in nuclear science and technology, 1961 (Reel P-1028)
- D-371: National University of Teacher Education, Iran - Aid for institute for graduate studies and research in education, 1961 (Reel P-1028)
- D-372: American Institute of Biological Sciences - Biological sciences curriculum study, 1961 (Reel P-1028)
- D-373: University of Alaska - Research program in business, economics, and public administration, 1961 (Reel P-1028)
- D-374: Detroit College of Law - Support for law internship project, 1961 (Reel P-1028)
- D-375: Government of India - Handicraft development into the field of small industry, 1961 (Reel P-1028)
- D-382: National Council on Crime and Delinquency - Study of correctional institutions for juveniles, youthful and adult offenders, 1961 (Reel P-1028)
- D-383: Vanderbilt University - General support for school of engineering, 1961 (Reel P-1028)
- D-386: Experimental Programs of Urban Research, Education, and Extension (Ford Foundation initiated), 1961-1963 (Reel P-1028)
- D-387: Foreign Area Training Fellowship Program, 1962-1963 (Ford Foundation initiated), 1961 (Reel P-1028)
- D-389: University of Notre Dame - Latin American studies program, 1961-1963 (Reel P-1028)
- D-391: University of Illinois - Strenghtening of preparation for college teaching, 1961 (Reel P-1028)
- D-392: Ohio Wesleyan University - Youth corps chemical training program, 1961 (Reel P-1028)
- D-393: University of Missouri - Faculty seminar in modern mathematics, 1961 (Reel P-1028)
- D-394: University of Hawaii - Faculty study grants in Asian culture, 1961 (Reel P-1028)
- D-396: University of Chicago - Research in economics, 1961-1962 (Reel P-1028)
- D-399: University of Chicago - Center for the study of regulated industries, 1961 (Reel P-1028)
- D-402: Biological Research on Human Reproduction in India (Ford Foundation initiated), 1961-1963 (Reel P-1028)
- D-403: Cornell University; University of Istanbul - Development of the field of industrial relations at the university of Istanbul, 1961 (Reel P-1028)
- D-406: State university of New York, Long Island - Programs for training of secondary school teachers, 1961 (Reel P-1028)
- D-408: Interamerican Planning Society - Clearinghouse for planning education in Latin America, 1961-1962 (Reel P-1028)
- D-410: Northeast Public Education Conference - general support, 1961 (Reel P-1028)
- D-412: Stanford University - Graduate program of instruction in international food and agricultural economics, 1961-1962 (Reel P-1028)
- D-415: Citizens Research Council of Michigan - Research and information program to further effectiveness of Michigan constitutional convention, 1961 (Reel P-1028)
- D-418: West Philadelphia Corporation - Redevelopment of University City, 1961 (Reel P-1028)
- D-419: Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists - generl support, 1961 (Reel P-1028)
- D-425: American Association of Teachers of Chinese Language and Culture - Conference of teachers of chinese studies in American colleges and universities, 1961 (Reel P-1028)
- D-435: University of Southern California - Institute for advanced musical studies, 1961 (Reel P-1028)
- D-437: Graduate School of Public Affairs, State University of New York (SUNY) - Cooperative relationship between Graduate School of Public Affairs of State Univ. of New York and the Irish Institute of Public Administration, 1961 (Reel P-1028)
- D-438: Institute for the Study of Crime and Delinquency - Study of narcotics involvement in California youth auhority wards, 1961 (Reel P-1028)
- D-440: Board of Education of the School District of the City of Detroit - Action research project supplemental to the Great Cities project, 1961 (Reel P-1028)
- D-441: Wake Forest College - Experimental program of Asian studies, 1961 (Reel P-1028)
- D-444: University of Rome- Institute of Criminal Anthropology - Analysis of subculture of violence among youthful offenders, 1961 (Reel P-1028)
- D-449: Fellowship program in business administration and economics, 1962-1963 (Ford Foundation initiated), 1961 (Reel P-1028)
- D-450: Joint Council on Economic Education - Special publications program, 1961-1963 (Reel P-1028)
- D-452: Oklahoma State University - Development of industrial and technical education programs in underdeveloped areas, 1961 (Reel P-1028)
- D-457: State University of New York, Albany - Establishment of international education programs, 1961-1962 (Reel P-1028)
- D-458: North Western University; London University - Conference on African law, 1961 (Reel P-1028)
- D-463: Harvard University - Application of input-output techniques of the U.S. economy and problems of economic development in the U.S. and various countries, 1961 (Reel P-1029)
- D-465: University of Arizona - Institute for microengineering education and research, 1961 (Reel P-1029)
- D-468: The Music Library Association - American music history project, 1961 (Reel P-1029)
- D-474: American Public Health Association, Inc. - Role of expenditures for medical care in nation's economy, 1961 (Reel P-1029)
- D-476: Strenghening of the atlantic community through the Atlantic Institute (Ford Foundation initiated), 1961 (Reel P-1029)
- D-477: Syracuse University - general support, 1961 (Reel P-1029)
- D-482: George Washington University - Role of patents in business, 1961 (Reel P-1029)
- D-484: Travel and Study awards, FY1962 (Ford Foundation initiated), 1961 (Reel P-1029)
- D-485: University of Southern California - Business institute for social scientists and mathematicians, 1961 (Reel P-1029)
- D-486: Oklahoma State University - Graduate study stimulation program in engineering, 1961-1962 (Reel P-1029)
- D-490: Publication of catalogues of American museum collections (Ford Foundation initiated), 1961-1962 (Reel P-1029, Reel P-1030)
  Approval of appropriation for a five-year program of matching grants to American museums for the publication of catalogues of their visual arts collections. $475,000 for 5 years. Includes correspondence to/from Andrew Carnduff Ritchie (1907-1978).
  See also files documenting grants for publication of catalogues made to Founders Society Detroit Institute of Arts (06700126, PA67-126), Wichita Art Museum (06900535, PA69-535), Bates College (06900536, PA69-536), and Museum of Fine Arts (06900537, PA69-537).
- D-492: Michigan State University (East Lansing) - Engineering educational development program, 1961-1962 (Reel P-1030)
- D-493: Pace College - Special program in education, 1961 (Reel P-1030)
- D-495: Grants-In-Aid to talented Artists (Ford Foundation initiated), 1958-1962 (Reel P-1030)
  See also: Ford Foundation records, Grants, 06290107 (PA92-107), Foundation-Administered Project (FAP), "PURCHASES UNDER THE FOUNDATION'S PROGRAM FOR THE PURCHASE OF WORKS BY AMERICAN ARTISTS".
  See also: Ford Foundation records, Projects, D-497: Collaboration of painters and sculptors in production designs of local theater and opera groups.
  See also: Ford Foundation records, Projects, D-498: Opportunities for professional, community and academic choral directors.